(
"ai_sub_version": "3.3.0",
"generated_at": "2026-07-18T01:03:58.665649",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
鷹嶺ルイ生誕祭LIVE Luminous Stairs
Takane Lui Birthday Live: Luminous Stairs
3D新衣装お披露目 / 超重大告知あり
3D New Costume Reveal / Super Important Announcement!
鷹嶺ルイ生誕LIVE 「Luminous Stairs」
Takane Lui Birthday Live "Luminous Stairs"
走りなさい 早く
Run, quickly,
もっと 早く
even faster,
悲しみに追いつかれないように
so that sadness won't catch up to you.
探しなさい 明かりのともる道を
Search for the path lit by light,
それは それは まばゆいでしょう
for it must be so very dazzling.
挑みなさい 君の
Challenge them,
美しさや 尊さを 傷つけるものに
the things that wound your beauty and preciousness.
眠りなさい 疲れたなら眠りなさい
Sleep, if you are tired, sleep,
神話をもたないあの星座のように
like that constellation with no myth of its own.
手を離したあと 君は気づくだろう
After you let go of my hand, you will realize
指の形 体温 その名残に
from the shape of the fingers, the warmth, and their traces,
胸を刺す
piercing your chest.
忘れたことも 忘れてしまえ
Forget even the things you have forgotten.
悲しみも温もりも消えてしまえ
May the sadness and warmth all disappear.
されど今も耳に残るは
Yet, what still remains in my ears
手酷く咲いた色なき世の...
is the colorless world cruelly blooming...
さよなら
Goodbye...
踊りなさい 誰に
Dance, even if
笑われても
everyone laughs at you...
淡雪を払う
brushing off the light snow
エトワールのように
like an étoile.
叫びなさい
Scream,
心から叫びなさい
scream from the bottom of your heart.
ここに確かに
Let it echo
生きたんだと 響かせて
that you certainly lived here.
行き合いの空に
Distant fireworks blur
遠花火が滲む
in the shifting sky.
帰るべき家を探す
If you are to embark on a journey
長い長い旅路を
to find the home you should return to...
行くなら
if you are to go...
高鳴るなら
If it throbs,
その心臓は
that heart of yours
最後のひと打ちまで
is yours
君のものだ
until its very last beat.
涙 涙
Tears, tears,
憧れる街
in the city of your dreams...
その一歩が 君の
that single step will set up
回り舞台を仕立てるだろう(そう)
your revolving stage.
さよなら
Goodbye...
それは千年の
That was a thousand years
ホームシックでした
of homesickness,
無限さえも
even after
数え終えて
counting up to infinity.
怪物のような
In a corner
世界の隅っこで
of a monster-like world,
戦い続ける人
the one who keeps fighting,
君はエルプ エルプ
you are Elp, Elp...
旅は続く
The journey continues.
忘れたことも
Before you even forget
忘れてしまうまえ
what you have forgotten,
悲しみも温もりも
let sadness and warmth
消えちまえ
both disappear.
いいよ もう いいよ もう
It's fine, it's fine,
二度と会うことは
never meeting again,
固く繋いだ手を
a goodbye like releasing
離すような さよなら
tightly held hands.
さよなら
Goodbye...
IRIS OUT
ダメ ダメ ダメ
No, no, no,
脳味噌の中から
from inside my brain,
「やめろバカ」とわめくモラリティ
the morality that screams "stop it, you fool!"
ダーリン ベイビー ダーリン
Darling, baby, darling,
半端なくラブ！と煌めき浮き足立つフィロソフィー
love me completely! A shimmering, light-footed philosophy.
死ぬほど可愛い上目遣い
An upturned look so cute it's to die for,
何がし法に触れるくらい
enough to violate some kind of law.
ばらまく乱心
Scattering wild madness,
気づけば唐人
before I know it, I'm a stranger.
この世に生まれた君が悪い
You, who were born into this world, are to blame.
やたらとしんどい恋煩い
A ridiculously painful lovesickness,
バラバラなる頭とこの身体
my head and this body are falling to pieces.
けど頸動脈からアイラブユーが噴き出て
But from my carotid artery, "I love you" gushes out...
アイリスアウト
...iris out!
一体どうしよう この思いをどうしよう
What on earth should I do? What should I do with these feelings?
あばらの奥をざらめが溶けて
The rock sugar deep in my ribs is melting,
ゲロになりそう
I feel like I'll vomit,
瞳孔バチ開いて溺れ死にそう
my pupils dilating, I feel like I'm drowning and dying.
今この世で君だけ大正解
Right now, in this world, you alone are the grand prize.
ダーリン ダーリン
Darling, darling,
darling, darling.
ダーリン ダーリン
Darling, darling,
darling, darling.
ひっくり返っても勝ちようない
Even if I flip over, I can't win,
君だけルールは適用外
the rules don't apply to you alone.
四つともオセロは黒しかない
All four corners of the Othello board are black,
カツアゲ放題
an all-you-can-extort offer.
君が笑顔で放ったアバダケダブラ
The "Avada Kedavra" you cast with a smile
デコにスティグマ 申し訳ねえな
leaves a stigma on my forehead—I have no excuse.
矢を射して 貫いて
Shoot an arrow, pierce through,
ここ弱点
here is my weak point.
死ぬほど可愛い上目遣い
An upturned look so cute it's to die for,
何がし法に触れるくらい
enough to violate some kind of law.
ばらまく乱心
Scattering wild madness,
気づけば唐人
before I know it, I'm a stranger.
この世に生まれた君が悪い
You, who were born into this world, are to blame.
パチモンでもいい なんでもいい
Even a cheap imitation is fine, anything is fine,
今 君と懐いてる全て欲しい
right now, I want everything that's attached to you.
けど頸動脈からアイラブユーが噴き出て<
But from my carotid artery, "I love you" gushes out...
アイリスアウト
...iris out!
Iris out!
アイリスアウト
Iris out...
一体どうしよう この思いをどうしよう
What on earth should I do? What should I do with these feelings?
あばらの奥をざらめが溶けて
The rock sugar deep in my ribs is melting,
ゲロになりそう
I feel like I'll vomit,
瞳孔バチ開いて溺れ死にそう
my pupils dilating, I feel like I'm drowning and dying.
今この世で君だけ大正解
Right now, in this world, you alone are the grand prize.
世界
...world
Darling Darling Darling...
永遠の意味 知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
It's time to show the answer to you, who knows not the meaning of eternity.
夢幻に続く螺旋の先へ
To the end of the spiral leading to fantasy...
言い訳に聞こえた理由は
The reason it sounded like an excuse is
儚い未来 手繰った弱さ
the weakness of reaching for a fleeting future.
それを強さとはき違えている
You are mistaking that for strength.
憎い 憎い 醜い 醜い
I hate you, how ugly,
月を隠すほどの
enough to obscure the moon...
黒く 黒く 淀む 心
a dark, stagnant heart.
君さえ居なければ
If only you weren't here.
ゆらいでる ゆらいでる
Swaying, swaying,
花のように意志を繋ぐ
connecting our wills like a flower.
奪っていく 奪っていく
Taking away, taking away,
嵐のように心を裂く
rending the heart like a storm.
永遠の意味 知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
It's time to show the answer to you, who knows not the meaning of eternity.
夢幻に続く螺旋の先に
At the end of the spiral leading to fantasy...
待つのは誰
Who is it that waits?
生まれ落ちた運命を飲んだ
Accepting the fate I was born with,
背負った数の名前を覚えた
I remembered the names of those I carry.
爛れるほど 心燃やす感情
An emotion that burns the heart to the point of blistering.
憎い 憎い 醜い 醜い
I hate you, how ugly,
世界を分かつほどの
enough to divide the world...
怒り 怒り 燃やす 心
a heart burning with anger.
君さえ居なければ
If only you weren't here.
ゆらいでる ゆらいでる
Swaying, swaying,
花のように意志を繋ぐ
connecting our wills like a flower.
奪っていく 奪っていく
Taking away, taking away,
嵐のように心を裂く
rending the heart like a storm.
永遠の意味 知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
It's time to show the answer to you, who knows not the meaning of eternity.
夢幻に続く螺旋の先へ
To the end of the spiral leading to fantasy...
鬼哭に耳を傾けた仕舞よ
I ended up listening to the wailing of spirits.
この身に宿る万物で終いよ
It ends with everything dwelling within this body.
夢幻を他者に託した弱き人
The weak who entrusted their fantasy to others,
きっと
Surely...
命の輝きは幾星霜に
The brilliance of life over countless years,
祈りの瞬きが照らす夕陽に
illuminated by the blinking of prayers in the setting sun,
千夜を身に宿し
harboring a thousand nights within,
解を押し付ける
imposing the solution.
枯らしていく 枯らしていく
Withering away, withering away,
夢幻の夜に花を裂く
rending flowers in the night of fantasy.
繋いでいく 繋いでいく
Connecting, connecting,
嵐に種を撒いていく
sowing seeds into the storm.
ゆらいでる ゆらいでる
Swaying, swaying,
花のように意志を繋ぐ
connecting our wills like a flower.
奪っていく 奪っていく
Taking away, taking away,
嵐のように心を裂く
rending the heart like a storm.
永遠の意味 知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
It's time to show the answer to you, who knows not the meaning of eternity.
夢幻に続く螺旋の先に
At the end of the spiral leading to fantasy...
待つのは誰
Who is it that waits?
お疲れ様！
Good job!
ということでね、にこに、来ていただきました！
And so, we have Niko joining us today!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！にこたんです！
Happy birthday! It's Nikotan!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
よく、お歌い切れたな
We really managed to sing it all the way!
なんかもうね、顔が... 顔はもう、涙...
I mean, my face... my face is already covered in...
涙で滲んでいる
...blurry tears.
「だ、大丈夫か？」って
"Are you... Are you okay?" she says!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
いやいや、ありがとうございます、こちらこそ。
No, no, thank you as well!
ということで、2026年の生誕祭はですね、
And so, for my 2026 birthday celebration,
あの、にこさんがゲスト出演ということで。
we have Nico-san appearing as a guest.
はい！
Yes!
あの、にこたんもね、3Dになったということで。
Since Nico-tan got her 3D model as well.
なりました！はい！
I did! Yes!
で、にこたんが「いつかルイ先輩の隣で歌いたい」って言ってくれてたので、
And since Nico-tan said she wanted to sing next to her Lui-senpai someday,
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you so much!
なので、今日は、お呼びさせていただきました！
I decided to invite her here today!
ありがとうございます、本当に！
Thank you so much, really!
いや、めちゃくちゃカッコいい曲を歌っていただきましたが、皆さんいかがでしたか？
We got to perform such a cool song together. What did everyone think?
いや、本当、嬉しかったです。にこたん良かったねって。
I was honestly so happy. They're saying, "Good for you, Nico-tan."
いやいや、もうにこたんのことはいいんです！
No, no, never mind about Nico-tan!
にこたん良かったねって。
"Good for you, Nico-tan."
そんなことよりですね、ルイ先輩、にこたんなんかより！
More importantly, Lui-senpai, forget about Nico-tan!
今日重大告知もあるし、新衣装もあるんですよ！
There's a major announcement today, and a new outfit!
そうなんです。新衣装もあるんです。
That's right. There's a new outfit too.
出るんでしたっけ？
Is it coming out?
これね、たくさんね、ここのハッシュタグ、
Yes. Please use this hashtag:
「#鷹嶺ルイ超重大生誕LIVE」ってありますんで、
"#TakaneLuiSuperMajorBirthdayLIVE"
それでたくさんたくさん、もうポストしてくれたら嬉しいなと思うんですけど、
I'd be so happy if you'd post a lot using it.
今日はたくさん、告知もありますし。
We have so many announcements today.
そうですよね！
That's right!
いや、にこたん気になるのも、もちろん重大告知の、デカさも気になるんですけど、
I mean, I'm curious about Nico-tan and how big the major announcement is, but...
新衣装がやっぱりね、気になる。
...I'm really curious about the new outfit.
やっぱりルイ先輩といえば、こう、ちょっとダークネスな感じなのかなとか。
When you think of Lui-senpai, you think of a sort of dark style, right?
黒い、黒系なのかな、みたいな。ああ、なるほど、なるほど。
Like black or dark colors. Ah, I see, I see.
そう思いますよね？
Don't you all agree?
はい。
Yes.
ま、それもあります。
Well, there is that aspect.
おお！それも？
Oh! That too?
ということは？最初ね、あの、固定でも書かせていただいたんですけど、
Which means...? I mentioned this in the pinned comment, but...
あの、新衣装は、最初はサブカラー。
...the new outfit starts with the sub-colors.
ええ？！で、ちょっと清楚な感じの衣装になっております。
What?! It has a somewhat elegant and pure feel to it.
え？それもあるって、他、他にもあるってこと？はい。
Huh? You have that, but does that mean there are others too? Yes.
めちゃくちゃ大量にサブを用意しておりますので、最後までね、楽しんで...
I've prepared a huge variety of options, so look forward to it...
キャー！なんか、なんかすごい騒いでる。
*screams* Wow, you're getting super excited.
おかしい、サブ、サブも？うん。
This is crazy! Sub... sub-colors too?! Yep.
もういいや、今日は来てくれてありがとう。
Anyway, thank you so much for coming today.
あ、分かりました！にこたん楽屋で応援してます！それでは！
Ah, alright! Nico-tan will cheer you on from the dressing room! Goodbye!
あ、違います、違います。そ、そちらの舞踏会会場なんで、
Ah, wait, not that way. That way leads to the ballroom, so...
ここ、ダメなんですか？にこたん。はい。
Is Nico-tan not allowed in here? Yes.
にこたんは呼んでない。招待状、もらってないでしょ？
Nico-tan wasn't invited. You didn't get an invitation, right?
もらってないけど...うん。
Well, no, but... Exactly.
じゃあ、あの、すいませんが楽屋の方にあちらから。嫌だー！
So, excuse me, but please head to the dressing room from over there. No way!
はい、スタッフさん、お願いします！はい！
Staff, please assist her! Yes!
ルイ先輩、タッチ、タッチだけでも！ありがとう、ありがとう。
Lui-senpai, just a high-five! Just a high-five! Thank you, thank you.
頑張ってください！ありがとうね、ありがとうね。
Do your best! Thank you so much.
ありがとうね。
Thank you.
ということで、にこたんに来ていただきました。はい、新衣装もね、たくさん見せていきますので、
And so, Nico-tan paid us a visit. Yes, I'll be showing off lots of new outfits,
最後まで楽しんでいただけたらなと思います。楽屋のにこたんも楽しんでくださいね！
so I hope you enjoy the show until the very end. Nico-tan in the dressing room, enjoy yourself too!
それでは聞いてください、ZIG-ZAG。
Now then, please listen to "ZIG-ZAG".
One, two, three, four
狂わせて 囁いた
You whispered to drive me mad,
こびりついて離れぬは
Clinging to me and never leaving,
無味無臭の生活が 思いだせないや
I can't even remember my tasteless, odorless life.
忘れたいから歌った
I sang because I wanted to forget...
恨むことも 憎むことも
Resenting or even hating someone...
賢く割に合わなかった
...was too clever and didn't pay off.
これが君の結末ならば
If this is your end,
笑ってしまいたい
I just want to laugh it off.
嘘、嘘、嘘
Lies, lies, lies.
嘘つき
Liar.
痛い、痛い、痛いな 奇跡とかちょっとのぞいちゃって
It hurts, it hurts, having caught a glimpse of a miracle...
もう嫌、嫌、嫌 立ちが悪いわね
...I'm sick, sick, sick of it. You have a nasty streak, don't you?
無い、無い、無いな おかしいとこ全部えぐりとって
There's none, none, none. Gouging out all the strange parts...
悪評だって結構 好きに呼んでいいよ
...bad reputation is fine, call me whatever you like.
トラウマにバイバイしたいの Death, death, death
I want to say bye-bye to my trauma. Death, death, death.
私 甘え上手になれなかった
I couldn't become good at playing coddled,
可愛げとかが足りなかった 後悔か？うるさいよもういい
I lacked cuteness. "Regrets?" Shut up, enough already.
過去は過去だと割り切っちゃえば きっと良いことあるさとか
If I just write off the past, "surely good things will happen" and so on...
これくらい百も承知だ
I know all of this all too well!
願うことも 祈ることも
Wishing or even praying...
許されないから黒く染めた
...aren't allowed, so I dyed it black.
元の色も思い出せない
I can't even remember the original color.
狂った運命の
This twisted fate's...
糸、糸、意図、糸
...thread, thread, thread, thread.
痛い、痛い、痛いな 悲劇のヒロイン気取っちゃって
It hurts, it hurts, pretending to be the tragic heroine...
もう嫌、嫌、嫌 諦めちゃえばいいのに
...I'm sick, sick, sick of it. Even though I should just give up.
会いたい、会いたい、会いたいな 信号が赤になっちゃって
I want to meet, meet, meet you. The traffic light turned red...
明日またきっと
...and surely, tomorrow again...
壊すけどいいの？
I'm going to break it, is that okay?
囚われ舞い散るの
Trapped and fluttering away.
デス デス デ デ デ デス
Death, death, de-de-de-death!
夢の中で君と手を繋いでいるの
In my dreams, I am holding hands with you,
何も知らないあの頃の二人のままで
just like the two of us back then, knowing nothing.
でも分かっているよ すぐに覚めてしまうと
But I know it well, that I will wake up soon.
それならばいっそ 君の手でそっと
If that's the case, then rather, by your hand, softly...
トドメを刺して
deal the finishing blow.
ほら 今 今 今
Look, now, now, now!
奪いたい奪いたい奪いたいな 奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
I want to steal, steal, steal it, hoping for a bit of a miracle,
もう 嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌
No more, no, no, no, no, no!
タチが悪いわ
This is so nasty.
足りない足りない足りないな おかしいとこ全部抉り取って
It's not enough, not enough, gouge out all the strange parts,
拍手喝采で結構
applause is perfectly fine.
お好きに呼んでいいよ
Call me whatever you like.
囚われる前に バイバイしたいの
Before I get caught, I want to say bye-bye.
デス デス デ デ デ デス
Death, death, de-de-de-death,
death, death, de-de-de-death!
アイのシナリオ
[Song: Ai no Scenario]
世界欺く揺るぎない正義
An unwavering justice that deceives the world,
ほどいて真実この手の中
unravels, bringing the truth into these hands.
大胆不敵な影が華麗に踊る
A daring, fearless shadow dances gracefully,
君が隠してる秘密いつか聞かせてよ
tell me the secret you're hiding someday.
伸ばした手で触れる事は誰もできない
No one can reach out and touch it,
君が隠してる世界僕に見せてよ
show me the world you're hiding.
揺れる難解な心
A wavering, complex heart,
解き明かして奪うその瞳
solving the mystery, stealing away those eyes.
不安がって泣いてたって見つかんないよ
Even if you cry in anxiety, you won't find it,
狙う真実はどこへ消えた
where did the truth we're aiming for vanish to?
たとえ
Even if...
世界欺く解答（こたえ）だとしても
even if it's an answer that deceives the world,
信じて差し出す掌
I'll believe and hold out my palm.
決して逃げない怖くは無いから
I'll never run away, because I'm not afraid,
目を開け弱さをかき消すんだ
open your eyes and drown out the weakness!
繰り返される運命に君は気づいてる？
Have you noticed the repeating fate?
僕が隠してる秘密いつか聞かせるよ
I'll tell you the secret I'm hiding someday.
歩み寄る偽りの影君は知らない
You don't know the false shadow approaching,
芽生えた記憶は絡む必然の棘で
the budding memories are tangled in inevitable thorns.
守りたい想いでただ
Simply with the desire to protect,
立ち向かって解（ほど）くその絆
I'll stand tall and untie those bonds.
何度だって助けるって揺るぎはしないよ
I will save you as many times as it takes, I won't waver,
隠す真実はどこへ消えた
where did the hidden truth vanish to?
たとえ
Even if...
世界を敵に回したとしても
even if I turn the whole world against me,
「信じて」僕だけ未来も
believe in only me, and our future too,
決して逃げない迷いは無いから
I'll never run away, because I have no doubts,
シナリオ壊して抗うんだ
I'll destroy the scenario and fight back!
世界を敵に回したとしても
Even if I make the world my enemy,
信じて 差し出す 手のひら
trust me, and hold out your hand.
決して離さない 想いは届いた
I will never let go, my feelings have reached you.
結んだ運命 この手の中
This bound destiny is in our hands.
繰り返された 答えだとしても
Even if it's an answer that repeats itself...
決して
Never...
逃げない 怖くは無いから
will I run away, because there's nothing to fear.
抗うんだ
I will fight back.
何度も 何度も 走り続けるよ
Over and over again, I'll keep running on!
Wake up! 闘志オンにして
Wake up! Turn on your fighting spirit!
Shift up! ギア回して
Shift up! Shift the gears!
Speed up! 羽ばたいて
Speed up! Spread your wings!
U.M.A. NEW WORLD!
Jump up! てっぺんへ
Jump up! To the very top!
Turn up! 声合わせて
Turn up! Join our voices!
Dream on! 未来繋いで
Dream on! Connect our futures!
U.M.A. NEW WORLD!
最高潮コンディション 闘志ガンガン尖ってこう
Peak condition! Let's sharpen our fighting spirit!
栄光のチャンピオン 虎視眈々と狙ってこう
Glory's champion! Let's watch vigilantly for our chance!
ハイペースにマイペース
High pace, my pace,
気合いレースに超集中
super focused on this energetic race!
駆ける背中は限界突破 ハートに火をつけて
Running past limits, setting our hearts on fire!
U.M.A. Let's go!
最高潮アディクション 互い掲げた勝負
Climax addiction! The challenge we laid down together,
千載一遇のチャンスを 全力出して掴んでこう
let's give it our all and seize this once-in-a-lifetime chance!
ハイペースにマイペース
High pace, my pace,
気合いレースに猛集中
intensely focused on this energetic race!
駆けるフォームをセットして 熱くちぎってこう
Set your running form and tear through passionately!
友と二人 競い合った 風の中でも
Competing together with a friend, even through the wind,
大きな背中 追いかけてた 雨の中でも
chasing that great back, even in the rain,
何百何千回と 積み重ねてきた
hundreds, thousands of times, we have built this up.
だからどこまでも遠く どこまでも高く
So, no matter how far, no matter how high,
誰よりも早く 誰よりも強く
faster than anyone, stronger than anyone!
さあ、今！
Now, let's go!
駆け出した想いは もう止まらない
The feelings we started running with won't stop!
誰にも渡せない ゴールまで
We won't let anyone else have it, until the goal!
弱気な気持ち 蹴飛ばして
Kick away any timid feelings,
一歩だってずっと 立ち上がって走り抜け
always standing up for every single step, run through!
鳴り出した鼓動は 収まらない
The beating heart that started thumping won't settle down,
最後まで 全身 全霊をかけて
to the very end, putting our whole body and soul into it!
頂点へ手を伸ばして 限界さえ超えてゆく
Reach out for the top, surpassing even our limits!
伝説を追い越して 勝利へと
Overtake legends on the path to victory!
友と二人 競い合った あの喜びも
Competing together with a friend, even that joy,
大きな背中 追いかけてた あの憧れも
chasing that great back, even that aspiration,
何千万回と 生まれ変わっても
even if we are reborn tens of millions of times,
何度も
over and over...
over again...
走り続けるよ
we will keep running on!
駆け出した想いは もう止まらない
The feelings we started running with won't stop!
誰もが夢に見てる 未来まで
To the future that everyone dreams of!
弱気も傷も 迷いも 涙だってずっと
Fears, wounds, hesitation, and even tears, always...
全てを繋いでゆけ
Connect everything together and carry on!
さあ、今！
Now, let's go!
鳴り出した鼓動は 収まらない
The beating heart that started thumping won't settle down,
最後まで 全身 全霊をかけて
to the very end, putting our whole body and soul into it!
頂点へ手を伸ばして 限界さえ超えてゆく
Reach out for the top, surpassing even our limits!
伝説を追い越して 勝利へと
Overtake legends on the path to victory!
友と二人 競い合った あの喜びも
Competing together with a friend, even that joy,
大きな背中 追いかけてた あの憧れも
chasing that great back, even that aspiration,
何千万回と 生まれ変わっても
even if we are reborn tens of millions of times,
何度も
over and over...
over again...
走り続けるよ
we will keep running on!
呼び覚ませ 本能を
Awaken your instincts!
起こせ 波動を
Unleash the shockwave!
見つめて 戦場
Stare down the battlefield!
叫べ Breakout
Shout out, breakout!
Woah woah woah
Break, break, break out
阻んでく足音 悔しいのかな
Are you frustrated by the footsteps blocking your way?
錆び付いていた鎧を前に 狼狽えているのか
Are you losing your composure before this rusted armor?
荒れ果てた地 切り拓き 導くんだ
Forge a path through the desolate lands and lead the way!
目を逸らさず 歴史を塗り替えてやるさ
Without looking away, we'll rewrite history!
Dan, dan, dan, dan, dan, dan, 上がってく
Step by step, going higher and higher!
歓声 巻き起こして とどめ
Stir up the cheers and deliver the final blow!
Dan, dan, dan, dan, dan, dan, 迫ってく
Step by step, drawing closer and closer!
あと少し 攻め合う シンパシー
Just a little more, matching our fighting sympathy!
Tiger 挑みたい
Tiger, I want to challenge!
Fighter 掴みたい
Fighter, I want to seize!
fight on!
挑みたい
I want to challenge!
fight on!
掴みたい
I want to seize it!
fight on!
刻みたい
I want to carve it!
fight on!
伝えたい
I want to convey it!
革命の火蓋切って
Setting off the spark of revolution,
伝説の旗掲げてゆこう そう
let's raise the banner of legend!
さぁ
Now,
legend-changer
ロックに飛び込んで
dive into the rock!
熱狂起こす 当事者になれ
Create the craze and lead the way!
legend-changer
大胆に行こうぜ
let's make a bold move!
本能 醒ませ
Awaken your instincts,
感動 起こせ
stir up emotions,
伝説 刻んで
and carve your legend!
大地 蹴って 蹴って 蹴ってbreak
Kick, kick, kick off the ground and break out!!
長い長い 夢の旅路を
On this long, long journey of dreams,
一歩 また一歩と 確実に進んでいく
we take one step, then another, moving forward with certainty.
鋭い眼差しで見据える先に
Looking ahead with a sharp gaze,
みんなの笑顔があると信じて
believing that everyone's smiles are waiting there...
さぁ行くよ！鋭い眼差し！
Come on, let's go! Sharp gaze!
無数の足跡にみる栄冠を
The glory seen in countless footprints,
憧れにして終わらせるな
don't let it end as just a yearning.
託された夢が堰を切って
The entrusted dream bursts through the dam,
今、私の闘志へと変わってゆく
and now, it turns into my fighting spirit!
さぁ
Now,
legend-changer
ロックに飛び込んで
dive into the rock!
熱狂起こす 当事者になれ
Create the craze and lead the way!
legend-changer
大胆に行こうぜ
let's make a bold move!
本能 醒ませ
Awaken your instincts,
感動 起こせ
stir up emotions,
伝説 刻んで
and carve your legend!
大地 蹴って 蹴って 蹴ってbreak
Kick, kick, kick off the ground and break out!!
Wo-o-o wo-o-o...
Break, break, break out!!
potatoになっていく
[Song: Becoming Potatoes]
もう救えない スクラップばかりのブルペンじゃ
No saving it anymore, in a bullpen full of nothing but scrap metal
ちちな青春も お涙も それすらもないもんな
Cheap youth and tears, we don't even have those
相当に笑えない コメディのワンシーンもままならない
Truly not funny, can't even manage a single scene of comedy
冷めたチャウダーを ただ混ぜ合わした さもそんな人生さ
Just mixing cold chowder, such is life
掛け違えたボタンの身なりを
With the appearance of misbuttoned clothes,
いつのいつまで見ぬ振りしようか
how long will we pretend not to see it?
そうかい 抗弁のしようもないな
Is that so? There's no way to argue back
たまたま火事場に逃げ込んで
Happened to escape into a fire scene,
善かれと油を放り込んで
threw oil in, thinking it'd help,
生活も 計画も 全部がpotatoになっていく
and life, plans, they all turn into potatoes
ぐつぐつ明日が泡吹いて
The bubbling tomorrow is foaming at the mouth,
白目のままに茹で上がって
boiling up with white eyes open,
将来像 成功法 全部がpotatoになっていく
future images, success formulas, they all turn into potatoes
このままみんなで散り散らかして
Let's all just scatter around like this,
どろどろに未来を溶かして
melting the future into a gooey mess,
そんな暮らしのままでKUSHA KUSHAになっていこうぜ
living like that, let's get all crumpled up together!
もう時間がない 我等に見下す権利などない
There's no more time, we have no right to look down on others
有象無象が発した ブーイングも 今なら勲章さ
Even the boos uttered by the rabble are like medals now
相当に笑えない 誰だってそう言わざるを得ない
Truly not funny, anyone would have to agree
バカの一つ覚えのように空回って ただバターになっている
Spinning our wheels like we only know one trick, just turning into butter
始めはこんなつもりじゃなかった
At first, I didn't mean for this to happen
誰か信じてくれやしないか
won't someone please believe me?
一切、反証の余地はないが
There is absolutely no room for refutation, but...
あたかも何も知らぬ顔で
With a face pretending to know nothing,
ここぞと薪を投げ込んで
throwing firewood in at the perfect moment,
生活も 計画も 全部がpotatoになっていく
life, plans, they all turn into potatoes
こんがり明日が煮え切って
Tomorrow is thoroughly cooked,
姿見えぬほど燃え上がって
burning up so much you can't even see it,
将来像 成功法 全部がpotatoになっていく
future images, success formulas, they all turn into potatoes
このままみんなで散り散らかして
Let's all just scatter around like this,
どろどろに未来を溶かして
melting the future into a gooey mess,
そんなボウルの中で憂さ晴らしだとかしようぜ
let's blow off some steam inside that bowl!
そんな暮らしのままでKUSHA KUSHAになっていこうぜ
living like that, let's get all crumpled up together!
Welcome to the Wonderland ここでは誰もが身勝手な
Welcome to the Wonderland, here everyone is selfish.
How are you doing, Miss? うつむくトランプ這いつくばって
How are you doing, Miss? Downward-facing cards crawling on the ground.
遠ざかる月の Moonlight
The Moonlight of the receding moon...
どう足掻いても無駄 死ぬまで帰れない
...no matter how you struggle, it's useless. You can't return until you die.
不気味な猫が闇の中で嗤う
A creepy cat laughs in the darkness.
「こんなにも濡れてるじゃないか」
"Aren't you soaking wet like this?"
官能へ響く声にそっと耳を立て
Gently listening to the voice echoing into sensuality...
まるでアリスのように
...just like Alice.
殺さぬように 活かさぬように
Neither killing, nor letting live...
壊れるまで愛してあげる
...I'll love you until you break.
快楽は媚薬なの
Pleasure is an aphrodisiac.
どんな兵（つわもの）もやがて 犬のように跪（ひざまず）く
Even the strongest warrior will eventually kneel like a dog.
This love is so insane
そう、これは夢の中 お伽話が出てきてご機嫌
Yes, this is inside a dream, fairy tales come out and are pleased.
バースデーでもないのにご馳走 優しい仮面もずり落ちそうで
A feast even though it's not a birthday, the kind mask also seems to slip off.
ねえ、いつものままでいようよ
Hey, let's stay as we always are.
それも気付かないなら it's fine
If you don't even notice that, it's fine.
I'm dreaming
Somebody wake me up
お上品な拍手（クラップ）をして メリー・アンは走り
With polite applause, Mary Ann runs,
帽子屋がまたカラカラと笑う
and the Mad Hatter laughs clatteringly again.
誰もが皆、嘘で嘘を塗り潰すとき
When everyone covers up lies with more lies,
仮面の裏が見える
the back of the mask becomes visible.
犯すように 汚すように
As if violating, as if defiling...
千の記憶を咲かす花園
...a flower garden blooming with a thousand memories.
狂う蜜が欲しいなら
If you want the mad nectar,
膝を突き、地を這い、我を求めよ
fall to your knees, crawl on the ground, and beg for me.
さあ、心臓（ハート）を捧げて戴戴（ちょうだい）
Now, offer up your heart.
Yes, Your Majesty. I give all my heart for you.
殺さぬように 活かさぬように
Neither killing, nor letting live...
この狂気的（インセイン）なディーラーさえ愛している
...I love even this insane dealer.
踊らされた私は
I, who was made to dance...
THE QUEEN OF HEART
...am the Queen of Heart.
さよなら 甘い 街
Goodbye, sweet town...
私 を くれ た 人
...and the one who made me into me.
泣き 癖 笑い あい
Being a crybaby, laughing together,
理屈 の ない 喜び
a happiness without logic.
曖昧 未完成 の
Our vague, imperfect...
過ち 悟っ た けど
...mistakes I realized.
それは 恋 の 季節
That is love's season,
閃き は 戻ら ない
the spark won't come back.
シナリオ通りのカルマ
Karma according to the scenario
飛び越えてきた人生
A life leaped over and crossed
望みがなくなって
With all hope completely gone,
愛だけ残ったの
only love has remained.
それぞれの幸せ振りかざしても
Even if we brandish our respective happiness,
倒れないふたりで立っていようね
let's stand together as two who won't fall.
鮮やかでいてね
Please remain vivid,
そのまままでいてね
please stay just as you are.
消えない幻
A phantom that will never fade.
夢幻クライマックス
Dreaming Climax,
最後の夜 エンドレスを刻め斬新に
on this final night, engrave the endless novelty.
抱きしめても壊れないくらい
Hold me so tight that I won't break,
強く、なりすぎたから
because I have become far too strong.
あなたはわかんない
You just don't understand
おかえりからの孤独
the loneliness after saying "welcome home."
それでも無神経に
Even so, with complete apathy,
季節が巡っていく
the seasons keep revolving.
いつも褒めてくれた 叱ってくれた
You always praised me, you scolded me.
きっと楽になるし 寂しくなるね
I'm sure things will get easier, but I'll miss you.
忘れないでいてね
Please don't forget me,
憧れていてね
please keep admiring me.
朽ちない面影
An imperishable vestige.
だからディスティニー 時を超えて
So it's destiny, transcending time,
同じ地球 踏んでいられるわ
that we can stand on the same Earth.
魂だけ 側に置いてね
Just keep your soul by my side,
強く生きていけるの
so that I can live on strong.
夢幻クライマックス
Dreaming Climax,
最後の夜
on this final night,
エンドレスを刻め
engrave the endless...
斬新に 抱きしめても壊れないくらい
novelty, so tight that I won't break,
強く、なりすぎた
because I have become too strong.
さみしい
I'm lonely...
だからディスティニー 時を超えて
So it's destiny, transcending time,
同じ地球 踏んでいられるわ
that we can stand on the same Earth.
魂だけ 側に置いてね
Just keep your soul by my side,
強く生きていこうな
let's live on strong.
はい。ということで、
Well then,
ゲストパート見ていただきましたが、いかがだったでしょうか？
you've just watched the guest section, how did you like it?
本当にね、あの、ゲストの人とこういうことやりたい！っていうのを
We really got to realize our wish to do
実現させていただきましたー！
something like this together with the guests!
皆さん、出演ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much to everyone for appearing!
はい。詳しくはですね、明日の振り返り配信で
Yes. For more details, in tomorrow's review stream,
色々ね、裏話だったりとかをお話しさせていただこうかなと思いますので、ぜひ振り返り配信も来てください。
I'll talk about various behind-the-scenes stories, so please watch the review stream too!
そして、
And next,
いかがですか？新衣装は！いかがでしょうか？可愛いでしょ？
how do you like my new outfit? What do you think? Pretty cute, right?
たくさん、あの差分があったんですけど気づきましたか？まあ、気づきますよね。
There were many differences, did you notice? Well, of course you did!
最初は白い衣装から始まりまして、
We started off with the white outfits,
そして「うまぴょい伝説」ではですね、あの黒いパンツ姿で階段から、あそこの階段から登場したんですけれども、
and then for "Umapyoi Densetsu," I appeared from the stairs over there in black pants.
最初、みんな「あれ？ルイどこ？」みたいな、
At first, everyone was like, "Wait, where is Lui?"
感じになってて面白かったんですけど。
It was really funny to see.
なんかね、ウマ娘を知っている人は「まあ、あそこから来るんやろうな」ってなんか、後方腕組みしてたのがまた面白かったですね。
It was also funny how those who know Uma Musume folded their arms knowingly, thinking, "Well, she's probably coming from there."
はい。えー、この後ですね、えー、21時20分から、
Yes. And next, after this, starting at 21:20,
メンバー限定で撮影会もございますので、
we'll have a members-only photoshoot session,
そちらもぜひ、色んな差分を見せていきたいなと思いますので、撮影会もぜひ来ていただけたら嬉しいでございます。
where I want to show you different variations, so I'd be happy if you could come join the photoshoot!
はい。えー、重大発表はですね、この後、2曲あるんですけど、
Also, we have two more songs left,
えー、今から歌う曲の後で、えー、発表させていただきますので、ぜひ皆さん、ちょっと心待ちにしていただけたらなと思います。
and I will make a major announcement after the next song, so please look forward to it!
はい。えー、じゃあ次の曲はですね、鷹嶺ルイ・セカンドアルバム『ラピスラズリ』から1曲歌わせていただきます。
Alright, for the next song, I'll sing a track from Takane Lui's second album, "Lapis Lazuli."
「抗う君への鎮魂歌」です。お願いいします。
It is titled "Requiem for You Who Resist." Please enjoy.
抗う君への鎮魂歌
[Title: Requiem for You Who Resist]
正しさだけ纏える術があれば
If only there was a way to wrap myself in righteousness...
少しは救われるだろうか
...would I be saved even just a little?
その瞳へと問いかける
I ask those eyes of yours.
護るべきを捨てるべきと 誰かにかどわかされても
Even if someone tries to deceive me into discarding what I must protect...
心通わないなら
If our hearts do not connect...
それは狂気だ
...then that is madness!
何も捨てずに
Without discarding anything,
抗う力なき者じゃ
with no power to resist...
その覚悟なき創造に 正しさなどない
...there is no righteousness in a creation without resolve.
失えば失うほどに更に気高く
The more I lose, the more sublime...
その意志で世界を怨め
...I hate this world with that resolve.
心が軋んで何度引き裂かれようと
Even if my heart creaks and is torn apart over and over...
抗え
...resist!
か弱き一人を守り抜くための",s:
To protect a single fragile soul...
この掌がどれだけ汚れてしまっても
...no matter how dirty these hands of mine become...
構わないさ 君が笑うなら
I do not care, as long as you smile.
僕は何にでもなる
I will become anything.
浅ましい擬態へつらうだけなら
If we only flatter wretched imitations,
人も獣も何一つ変わらない
then humans and beasts are not one bit different.
鎖に似た自由を
While lamenting a freedom that resembles chains,
嘆いては歪に愛でるのでしょう
we probably cherish it in a distorted way.
どうか君だけは
Please, at least you...
僕を覚えていて欲しい
...must remember me.
必ず君を自由へと誘う
I will surely lead you to freedom.
俯けば俯くほどに更に気高く
The more I look down, the more sublime...
その意志で世界を揺らせ
...I shake the world with that resolve.
心が歪んで何もかもが崩れても
Even if my heart is warped and everything crumbles...
抗え
...resist!
か弱き一人を守り抜くための
To protect a single fragile soul...
この掌がどれだけ汚れてしまっても
...no matter how dirty these hands of mine become...
構わないさ 君が笑うなら
I do not care, as long as you smile.
何度だって壊してみせる
I will break it all as many times as it takes.
心から君が笑えた時
When you can smile from the bottom of your heart...
僕は報われるのだろう
...will I finally be rewarded?
消えかけた夢に
To a fading dream...
ホロホロだけど
...even though it is fragile.
12.16
December 16
不安も、否定も、葛藤も。
Anxiety, denial, and conflict.
私が歌で「反逆」する。
I will "rebel" through my song.
1st Live 開催決定
1st Live Concert Confirmed!
venue Kanadevia Hall
REBELLION Takane Lui 1st Live
Takane Lui 1st Live: REBELLION
ここから始まる。私だけの物語。
It begins here. My own story.
はい！ということで！
All right! And so!
私、鷹嶺ルイの初めてのソロライブが決定しました！
My very first solo concert, Takane Lui's 1st Live, has been confirmed!
イェーイ！フーー！
Yay! Woohoo!
ということで、日程は、半年後になる...なるのですが
And so, the date will be in half a year...
半年後の2026年12月16日水曜日となっております！
...specifically Wednesday, December 16, 2026!
ね。会場はカナデビアホールです！
And the venue is Kanadevia Hall!
もうね、4月の末にホロックスライブがありまして
We had the holoX Live at the end of April,
そして9月にね、ポックスがありまして
then Nepox in September,
そして12月に鷹嶺ルイのソロライブがあるということで
and now in December, I'll have my solo live!
1年ね、2026年はすごい楽しめる
This whole year of 2026 is going to be
年になるんじゃないですか？ルイ友さん。
an incredibly fun year, don't you think, Luitomo?
はい。ということで、ルイ友さんにはね、色々お話ししたことがあると思うんですけれども
So, I think I've mentioned this to you all before,
私は前々からですね、今まで音楽活動を
but for a long time, through my musical activities,
えー、で、道を作ってきてくれた先輩。そら先輩だったり
seeing the seniors who paved the way, like Sora-senpai,
すいちゃん、あずちゃん、そしてわため、そしてカリ先輩のようにですね
Sui-chan, AZ-chan, Watame, and Calli-senpai,
ファーストライブから少しずつ、段階、階段を上がっていって
I've always admired the story of starting from a first live
広い会場でソロライブをするという、そんな物語に憧れていました。
and gradually climbing the steps to a massive venue.
だから、もし私がライブをやることになった際には
So, if I ever got to do lives,
ファースト、セカンド、サード、フォースと
I wanted to do a first, second, third, and fourth live,
順々に会場を大きくしていって
gradually increasing the venue size,
ゆくゆくはアリーナという夢を叶えたい。
and eventually fulfilling my dream of an arena live.
はい。そう思っていて、ルイ友さんには常々お伝えをしていたと思います。
Yes, that's what I thought, and I've always shared this with you.
そのためにね、定期的なソロライブができる活動を頑張りたいなと思って
To make that happen, I wanted to work hard on regular solo lives,
今まで努力をしてきました。そしてこれからもします！
and I've put in the effort. I'll keep working hard!
最近のホロライブはですね、結構
Recently, hololive has been holding concerts
より多くの方が入る会場での開催が多くて
mostly in venues that accommodate a lot of people,
私の夢はちょっと難しいのかなとは、思っていたんですけれども
so I wondered if my dream might be a bit difficult...
こうやって、私の夢を理解してくださり、叶えるべく
But they understood my dream, and to help me achieve it,
まずは私の希望だったカナデビアホールにて
first, they are letting me hold my first live
ファーストライブをやらせていただくことになりました！おめでとう、ありがとう！
at my dream venue, Kanadevia Hall! Thank you so much!
そして、あのトレンドもありがとうございます。ありがとうございます。
And thank you for getting me on the trending list as well!
ここからが鷹嶺ルイの新章の
This marks the beginning of a new chapter,
新章の物語の始まりでございます。
a new story for Takane Lui.
まずはファーストライブを開催してから、次を考えるべきだとは思うんですけれども
I know I should probably get through the first live before thinking about the next step,
私はセカンド、サード、フォース
but I've already thought ahead to the second, third, fourth,
その先のライブへのビジョンまで考えております！
and the vision for lives beyond that!
今回の生誕ライブのタイトルでもあるように
Just like the title of this birthday live,
ルミナスステアーズ、輝かしい階段を駆け上がるために
to run up the 'Luminous Stairs'—the brilliant staircase,
そして、一緒にこの物語を紡いでいくために
and to weave this story together with you,
少しでも行きたいなと思ってくださった方は
if you feel even a slight desire to come,
次に繋げるために、応募したりライブを見てくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you applied or watched to help pave the way!
ライブのタイトルは、リベリオンになっております。
The title of the live is 'REBELLION'.
はい、リベリオンです。
Yes, Rebellion.
はい、反逆という意味でございます。
Yes, it carries the meaning of 'rebellion'.
私がいつも抱えてる不安や、そして色々な否定の声
The anxieties I always carry, the various critical voices,
そして、私自身の葛藤
and my own inner conflicts—
これからも私は、それを私の歌で反逆していきたい。
I want to rebel against all of that through my songs.
そんな気持ちで、込めて、つけさせていただきました。
With those feelings in mind, I chose this title.
最高のライブになるようにたくさん準備をしていますので
I'm preparing extensively to make this the best live ever,
ぜひ楽しみに待っていてください！
so please look forward to it!
はい、ここからまた新たに鷹嶺ルイの物語が始まるということで
Yes, with my story starting anew from here,
アーティスト写真を作りました！こちらです。
we made new artist photos! Here they are.
はい、めちゃくちゃかっこいいですね。かっこかわいい。
Yes, they are incredibly cool. Cool and cute.
はい、アーティスト活動の際には
I plan to use these during my artist activities,
こちら使っていこうかなと思っておりますので、よろしくお願いいたします。
so please look forward to seeing them.
かつ、ここまでファースト、セカンド、アコースティックとアルバムを作ってきましたが
And while I've released my first, second, and acoustic albums,
今回、ライブを盛り上げるために
this time, to get everyone hyped for the live,
4曲、新しく作りまして
I've newly created 4 songs!
収録させていただいたミニアルバムも本日ライブ終了後に予約開始です！
The recorded mini-album will be available for pre-order right after the live!
ね。たくさん曲がありますね、鷹嶺ルイ。
Right? I have so many songs now, don't I?
はい、えー、「LEGENDARY」というタイトルをつけさせていただきましたミニアルバムでございます。
Yes, I've titled this mini-album 'LEGENDARY'.
この後に披露する新曲も入っております。
It also includes the new song I'll perform later.
えー、完全生産限定盤には、全員に、サインがつきます。
And the Limited Edition comes with a signature for everyone.
完全生産限定盤には全員に、直筆サインがつきますので
Yes, the Limited Edition features a hand-signed autograph for everyone,
ぜひ
so please get it!
日頃の感謝を込めてサインを書きますので、ぜひ予約してください。
I'll sign them with all my gratitude, so please pre-order!
お求めやすい通常盤もあります。こちらはちょっとサインついてないんですけど
We also have an affordable Regular Edition, though it doesn't have a signature.
通常盤もございますので、ぜひお手元にとっていただけますと嬉しいです。
We have the Regular Edition too, so I'd love for you to get a copy.
今回のライブ、そして、この後に予約開始される
The hashtag for this live and the mini-album
ミニアルバムのハッシュタグは共通で、「#鷹嶺ルイの反逆」となっております。
available for pre-order afterward will be '#TakaneLuiNoHangyaku'.
皆さんたくさんポストして盛り上げてくださいね。
Please post a lot to build up the excitement!
ビジュよいっしょ。ビジュよいよね。
The visuals are great, right? They look really good.
以上、ソロライブとミニアルバムの告知でした。
That's all for the solo live and mini-album announcements.
まだ、お知らせはございます。
But wait, we have even more news!
はい、お知らせと重大告知がございます。
Yes, we have announcements and major news!
次はお待ちかねのグッズ紹介です！はい、こちら。
Next is the long-awaited merchandise intro! Here it is.
鷹嶺ルイ誕生日記念2026ということで
This is the Takane Lui Birthday Celebration 2026!
キービジュアルは今回お披露目させていただいた
For the key visual, I'm wearing the new outfit
新衣装を着てケーキを食べている鷹嶺ルイです
that was just unveiled, eating cake!
久乃のらり先生に写真を撮っていただきました 可愛いでしょ
Norari Hisano-sensei drew this illustration. Cute, right?
それでは1つずつ見ていきましょう
Let's take a look at the items one by one.
はい 1つ目はこちら
Yes! First up is this:
アクリルジオラマスタンドになっております
the Acrylic Diorama Stand!
ルイ友さんとがんもも可愛く執事風におめかしをしてます 可愛い
The Luitomo and Ganmo are also dressed up cutely like butlers. So cute!
はい 続いてはこちら
Okay, next is this one!
新衣装についている2種類のエンブレムを
These pin badges are modeled after the two types of emblems
モチーフにしたピンバッジでございます
featured on my new outfit.
色んなところにつけて密かにルイ友アピールをしてください オシャレでしょ
Put them on to subtly show you're a Luitomo! Stylish, right?
はい 続いてはこちら
Yes! Next is this one.
新衣装をモチーフにしたポーチになってます オシャレ
This is a pouch modeled after the new outfit. So stylish!
裏面はですね メッシュポケットになっているので
The back has a mesh pocket,
缶バッジや今回販売するピンバッジも付けやすいデザインです
designed to easily attach can badges or the pin badges!
最後は これ欲しかったんじゃないかな？こちら！
Finally, I bet you wanted this... Here it is!
新衣装のショートパンツバージョンの
It's a plushie of the short pants version
ホロフレと同じくらいのサイズのぬいぐるみです
in about the same size as Holo-Friends!
可愛い！ぜひこの機会にお迎えしていただけたら嬉しいです
Cute! I'd be so happy if you welcomed it home.
フルセット購入特典はこちら
The full set purchase bonus is this!
ポストカードになっておりまして 数量限定版と通常版がございます
It's a postcard, available in limited quantity and regular versions.
数量限定版は直筆サインが付きます たくさん用意しておりますので
The limited version comes with a handwritten autograph. I have plenty ready,
ゆっくり選んでください
so please take your time choosing.
販売は21時15分からカートオープンです
Sales will begin with the cart opening at 21:15.
はい 以上グッズ紹介でした
That's it for the merch showcase!
そしてもう1つ 重大告知です こちら！
And one more thing, a major announcement! Look here!
なんとbayfmさんにてレギュラーラジオの番組が決定しました！
Incredibly, a regular radio show on bayfm has been decided!
放送時間は毎週金曜日24時30分から24時57分
The broadcast time is every Friday from 24:30 to 24:57.
初回放送日は7月3日金曜日となっております
The first broadcast will be on Friday, July 3rd!
Xでも初回配信用のお便りを募集するので
We'll be accepting messages on X for the first episode,
メールアドレスも公開しますので Xのフォローをよろしくお願いします
so please follow my X account for the mail address!
はい 次の曲が最後の曲になります
Okay, the next song will be the last one.
先ほど紹介させていただきました新曲で 名前は Soar と言います
It's the new song I introduced earlier, titled "Soar."
ソロライブでもみんなと一緒に歌いたいなと思って
I wanted to sing it with everyone at my solo live,
みんなが声出しできる新曲を作ってきました
so I made this song where everyone can shout along!
七星さんに書き下ろしていただいた爽やかな楽曲になっております
It's a refreshing track written for me by Nanahoshi-san.
この後21時から ミュージックビデオのプレミア公開もあります
After this, from 21:00, there will be a MV premiere!
楽曲は本日24時にリリースです
The digital song will release tonight at 24:00.
この曲はコーラスをホロメンが歌ってくれております
The chorus was sung by other Hololive members!
ライブまでにたくさん聴いて覚えてくれたら嬉しいです
I'd be happy if you memorized it before the live.
それでは早速聴いていただきましょう Soar です どうぞ
Now, let's listen to it right away. Here is "Soar"!
何度でも君を呼んで また歩いてゆく
No matter how many times, I will call your name and keep walking forward.
一歩 踏み出したらもう未来さ
Once you take a step forward, it's already the future.
昨日 つまずいた道も 今日からは近道だ
Even the path where we stumbled yesterday is a shortcut from today.
息をするたびに広がる景色
With every breath, the landscape expands.
私を信じていいと言って
Tell me that it's okay to believe in myself.
つぶやきも希望になって あふれては声になって
Even whispers turn into hope, overflowing into voices.
何度 目を閉じても 消せないな
No matter how many times I close my eyes, I can't erase it.
高く飛べるよ そうだろう 抑えられない
We can fly high, right? I can't hold it back.
羽ばたく理由を 誰かに 許されなくても
Even if we don't have anyone's permission to spread our wings,
もう決めたよ 迷わない
I've already decided, I won't hesitate.
向かい風も きっと進んでる証拠だって
Even the headwind is surely proof that we are moving forward.
君に伝えるんだ
I will convey it to you!
どんな重力も 心までは
No amount of gravity, not even in our hearts,
縛れない 曲げられない この手で確かめたい
can bind us or bend us. I want to verify this with my own hands!
胸 焦がした思いで 爪痕をさぁ刻んで
With a burning passion in my heart, let's leave our mark,
嵐の空模様 切り裂いて
tearing through the stormy sky!
もっと輝くよ そうだろう 叫べばいい
We'll shine even brighter, right? Just scream it out!
憧れより眩しい歌 そして激しい唄
A song more dazzling than longing, a passionate melody
いつか耳を塞いだ その両手が
Those hands that once covered your ears
きっと翼になる そう思うんだ
will surely become wings, I believe so.
ゆずれない衝動
An unyielding impulse!
Woah...
高く飛べるよ そうだろう 抑えられない
We can fly high, right? I can't hold it back!
羽ばたく理由を誰かに許されなくても
Even if no one permits our reason to take flight,
もう決めたよ 迷わない
I've already decided, I won't hesitate.
向かい風もきっと進んでる証拠だって
Even a headwind is proof we're moving forward.
君に伝えるんだ
I will tell you!
何度でも君を呼んで また歩いてゆく
I'll call your name again and again and keep walking.
皆さん、本日は生誕祭に来てくださってありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you so much for coming to my birthday celebration today!
ソロライブ、楽しみにしててね！
Please look forward to my solo live!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
ルイ友へ
みんなの応援のおかげで…ついに私もソロライブできるよぉ！！本当にありがとう♡
To Rui-tomo:
Thanks to everyone's support, I can finally do a solo live! Thank you so much! ♡
もっともっと夢にむかって光り輝く階段をのぼって、
いろんな景色をみせてね☺
Climbing up the shining stairs towards our dreams,
I'll show you many different sights! ☺
私の物語には君が必要です！！これからもよろしくね!!
[2026.06.11]
You are absolutely necessary for my story!!
I look forward to being with you from now on! [2026.06.11]